American Chicle Company Records
American Chicle Company Records
1889-1964
American Chicle Company.
114 linear ft.
Files and published material of the American gum and confectionery manufacturer.
2751593
Biographical History
The American Chicle Company was an American chewing gum company, incorporated in 1899. The company had operations in Brooklyn, Cleveland, Chicago, Louisville (Kentucky), and Toronto, as well as factories and forest land in Yucatan. Its products eventually grew to include breath mints, antacids, cough drops and other items. American Chicle was acquired by Warner-Lambert in 1962, which in turn was acquired by Pfizer in 2000.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The American Chicle Company Records contains administrative, legal and financial papers. The largest categories are legal papers, patent materials, and stocks information. The financial material consists entirely of bound volumes.
Included in the collection (particularly in the financial material) is also some material from subsidiary and/or partner companies, such as the Crawford Gum Company and the Mexican Exploitation Company.
Arrangement of the Collection
Lacking a company history or organizational chart, the American Chicle files have been arranged in a single alphabetical run by topic or type of file (e.g. legal files, patents, etc.) The majority of the material is in 43 boxes, but there are also some 389 bound volumes, most of these financial in nature (ledgers, journals, expense information, etc.)
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; American Chicle Company.; Candy industry -- Accounting.; Candy industry -- United States -- History.; Chewing gum -- United States -- History.; Chicle industry -- Mexico.; Confectionery -- United States -- History.; Advertisements.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Journals (accounts); Ledgers (account books); Legal documents.; Legal files.; Minutes (administrative records); Patents.; Reports.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, 1967.
Inventory
- General files
  - Adams Brands, Ltd. and Adams Brands Sales, Ltd.
    - Annual Meeting, 1953-1957; 1958; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Adams Chewing Gum Company, Ltd.
    - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
    - Liquidation, 1933 (Box 1)
  - American Bank Note Company
    - [General], 1944; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Chicle Company
    - Board of Transportation
      - Original and Supplemental Contract V-3, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1 through 135, 29 folders (Box 1)
    - Bonds
      - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1)
      - General, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
      - Sugar, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - By-Laws, 1922-1961; 6 folders (Box 2)
    - Christmas Bonus, 1940-1949 (Box 2)
    - Christmas Boxes to Stockholders-Correspondence, 1950-1957 (Box 2)
    - Claims
      - Foreign Substance
        - [General], 1953-1956; 1954,; 1955,; 1957; 4 folders (Box 2)
        - Summary, 1953-1956 (Box 2)
        - Canada, General, 1958 (Box 2)
      - General, 1950-1957 (Box 2)
      - Marine - S.S. Rozewie (Brazil (Box 2)
    - Department of Commerce, Commerce Clearing House (Box 2)
    - Employees Association #3, 1948-1958 (Box 2)
    - Insurance
      - Argentina, Fire, 1947 (Box 2)
      - Auto, General (Box 2)
      - Marine, Columbia correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
      - Personal, J. Hoppenfeld (Box 3)
      - Product Liability (Box 3)
    - Inter-Office
      - P.L. Becker (Box 3)
      - S.C. Davis (Box 3)
      - P. Freedman, 1954-1958 (Box 3)
      - R.L. Harris, 1957 (Box 3)
      - K.F. Hazelton (Box 3)
      - R. Heggie (Box 3)
      - J. Hoppenfeld, 1942-1945 (Box 3)
      - E.V. Moore, 1942-1957 (Box 3)
      - E. Murrell (Box 3)
      - Office Manager, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
      - J.S. Schastey, 1943-1957 (Box 3)
    - Legal
      - Adams Mint, Revised Formula (Box 3)
      - Advance Payment for Purchase of Supplies (Box 3)
      - Advertising
        - Adams Grape (Box 3)
        - Adams Wild Cherry (Box 3)
        - Beemans, Talent Payment Claim, A. Winfield Hoeny (Box 3)
        - Beemans, TV Copy: "Fun House Mirror," "Roller Coaster Nervous Stomach" Whirling Spring Acid Indigestion Commercial; 3 folders (Box 3)
        - Black Jack (Box 3)
        - Canada Chiclets 1-cent Promotion, Humpty Dumpty Potato Chip Co. (Box 3)
        - Chiclets, 1939-1957; 3 folders (Box 3)
        - Clorets (Box 3)
        - Clorets Mints (Box 3)
        - Clove (Box 3)
        - Crawfords Cough Gum (Box 3)
        - Dentyne, 1944-1955 (Box 3)
        - Dentyne Promotion, teenage market, 1962 (Box 3)
        - Display of Car Cards, United Cigar / Whelan Stores Corp. (Box 3)
        - Motion Picture, purchase of Healy film showing chicle gathering (Box 3)
        - Radio, Canada, "Take a Chance" Program (Box 3)
        - Radio, Mexico, "Take a Chance" Program (Box 3)
        - Radio, Television (Box 3)
        - Sen Sen (Box 3)
        - Special Promotion, Proposed Use of Chiclets Fruit Carton Design by Wonderknit Corp. (Box 3)
        - Yucatan (Box 3)
      - Advertising contracts, Domestic and Foreign, 1935-1950 (Box 3)
      - Advertising Signs, Trouble Alarm (Box 3)
      - Advertising Signs on Trucks Operated by Public Truckmen (Box 3)
      - Air Conditioning, offices and cafeteria, L.I.C., Rockford; approp. #5864 (claim against block partitions for water damage from rainstorm) (Box 3)
      - Air Transport Companies Distribution of Samples (Box 3)
      - Alcohol, New York State, 1951-1955 (Box 3)
      - Alcohol, Registration of Stills, 1935-1954 (Box 3)
      - Alcohol, Federal, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
      - Allergies, chewing gum (Box 3)
      - Annual Meetings of N.J. Corporation (Box 3)
      - Appeal of German Duty on Sen Sen and Sen Sen Tins (Box 3)
      - Argentina (Box 3)
      - Automobiles - Fleet Purchase Plan (Box 3)
      - Boiler and Engine Room Modernization (Box 3)
      - Brands and Packings
        - Correspondence, R.L. Harris, 1958-1960; 3 folders (Box 3)
        - Correspondence, R.L. Harris, 1961 (Box 4)
        - Correspondence, R.B. Kyle (Box 4)
        - Correspondence, T.H. Smith (Box 4)
        - General (Box 4)
        - W.D. Murphy (Box 4)
      - Building Main Entrance, Damage to Doors (Box 4)
      - Canada
        - "Made in U.S.A." (Box 4)
        - New Deal Legislation
          - Advertising Copy (Box 4)
          - General (Box 4)
          - Price Discrimination (Box 4)
      - Change in Company Name
        - Canada (Box 4)
        - Steps to be taken in event of change (Box 4)
      - Change in Officers (Box 4)
      - Chewing Gum a Food or Not a Food (Box 4)
      - Claims for Refund of Duty on Goods Destroyed in Bonded Warehouse (Box 4)
      - Clayton Act, "Discounts" (Box 4)
      - Contests (Box 4)
      - Contract
        - Aetna Freight Lines (San Francisco Warehouse (Box 4)
        - American District Telegraph Company (Box 4)
        - American Sugar Refining Co. (Box 4)
        - Amsco Packaging Machinery (Box 4)
        - Automatic Canteen Co., 1933-1955; 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Badger, Browning, and Hersey (Box 4)
        - Beech-Nut / American Chicle Company Joint Research Project at Mellon Institute (Box 4)
        - Brazil-Brown Bag Filling Machine Company (Box 4)
        - Brown sBag Filling Machine Company (Box 4)
        - Business Fleets, Inc. (Box 4)
        - Albert L. Calder Company (Box 4)
        - Campbell, Peterson and Co. (Box 4)
        - Champlain Corp. (Formerly known as Chamban Corp. (Box 4)
        - Chattanooga Medicine Co., May, 1955; proposed drafts (Box 4)
        - Chattanooga Medicine Company #2 (Box 4)
        - Claude Neon Lights, Inc. (Box 4)
        - Conley Foil Company (Box 4)
        - Frank Crossley (Box 4)
        - Dellenbarger-Penley (Box 4)
        - L.M. Demarest (Box 4)
        - Ralph L. Evans Association (Beech-Nut / H.C. Joint Research (Box 4)
        - Fontaine Box (Box 4)
        - Gum Vending Corporation, 1949-1951 (Box 4)
        - Horstmann Trucking Corporation (Box 4)
        - Tom Huston Peanut Company (Box 4)
        - Interborough News Co., 1936-1945 (Box 4)
        - Interborough News Co., 1946-1949 (Box 4)
        - Interborough Business Machine Corp. (Box 4)
        - International Paper Box Machine Company (Box 4)
        - H. Johnson (Canada (Box 4)
        - Keystone Chemurgic Corporation, Rolaids reformulation, HMA (Box 5)
        - Labor Union-San Francisco (Box 5)
        - L.I.R.R. Siding Agreement (Box 5)
        - Liability of Contractual Parties (Box 5)
        - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 5)
        - Royalty on Sales, 2% absentee tax, dividends (Box 5)
        - Munro-Matlack Company (Box 5)
        - National Rejectors, Inc., 1950-1952 (Box 5)
        - New York Subways Advertising Co., 1949 (Box 5)
        - Package Machinery Company (Box 5)
        - Pedro Del Rio, Jesus Diaz Cordoba (Box 5)
        - F.B. Redington Company Research, Inc. (Box 5)
        - Reynolds Metals Company Robinson Auto Rental Co. (Box 5)
        - Rohm and Haas Company, medicated brands, Enzyme Gum, Trident (Box 5)
        - Rowe Corporation (Box 5)
        - Sackett and Wilhelms (Box 5)
        - Sackett and Wilhelms, cafeteria service (Box 5)
        - Herbert L. Sanger (Box 5)
        - C.E. Schunack Co., Inc. (Box 5)
        - H.C. Seff, Ltd. (Box 5)
        - M.J. Seiwert Cartage Company (Box 5)
        - Sen Sen Formula
          - Mr. S.T. Britten (Box 5)
          - Mr. J.P. Phillips (Box 5)
          - Mr. C.L. Schastey (Box 5)
          - Mr. P.L. Becker (Box 5)
        - Stanford Research Institute (Box 5)
        - Strauss and Hedges (Box 5)
        - Sullivan-Stauffer-Colwell and Bayles, Inc. (Box 5)
        - Sylvania Industrial Corp., Sylphrap, Nymphrap (Box 5)
        - Texas State Research Foundation (Box 5)
        - Tufts College Dental School (Box 5)
        - U.S. Leather Goods Co. (Box 5)
        - U.S. Trucking Corporation (Box 5)
        - Vending Concession, Chicago Transit Authority (Box 5)
        - A. Weiss (Box 5)
      - Contracts
        - Automobile, 1950-1956 (Box 5)
        - Educational Trust (Box 5)
        - Employees Service Agreements-L.I.C., 1925-1955 (Box 5)
        - Export, 1928-1956; 5 folders (Box 5)
        - General, 1922-1958; 8 folders (Box 6)
        - Sales Arrangements (Box 6)
        - Francois L. Schwarz, Inc. (Box 6)
        - Special Sales Arrangements (Box 6)
        - U.S. Government (Box 6)
        - Vending, 1944-1949; 2 folders (Box 6)
        - Vending Association, New York City Transit System, 1955; 1956-1960; 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Copyright Infringement (Box 6)
      - Counterfeit Bill, A. Berman (Box 6)
      - Coupon in Packages (Box 6)
      - Mary B. Cushion Property (Box 6)
      - Danish Chiclet Company (Box 6)
      - Electric Current, Sackett and Wilhelms (Box 6)
      - Employee Benefit Plans
        - [General], 1935-1960; 2 folders (Box 6)
        - Canada (Box 6)
        - Major Medical Plan (Box 6)
        - Massachusetts Health, Welfare, and Retirement Disclosure Act (Box 6)
        - Pension Plan Modernization, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
        - Supplemental Pension Plan, Treasury Dept. Approval (Box 6)
      - Employment, 1936-1957 (Box 6)
      - Executive Committee (Box 6)
      - Federal Explosive License (Box 6)
      - P. Geiss, personal (Box 7)
      - Handling of Paper Delivered Orders Holidays (Box 7)
      - Honor Awards (Box 7)
      - Inspections
        - Electrical (Box 7)
        - Elevator (Box 7)
      - Laws
        - Brazil
          - Law of Similar Products (Box 7)
          - Reciprocal Trade Agreement (Box 7)
        - Fair Trade
          - California Price #1870 and #769 (Advertising Refunds, etc.) Bill (Box 7)
          - Federal Trade Commission, Anti-Trust (Box 7)
          - General, 1929-1955 (Box 7)
          - Lottery (Box 7)
          - Price Fixing-Miller Tydings Bill (Box 7)
          - Robinson-Patman Act-Chain Store Discounts, 5 folders (Box 7)
        - Labor
          - Anti-Inflation Act, 1944-1947 (Box 7)
          - Civil Rights' Law (Box 7)
          - Canada Wage and Hour Act (Box 7)
          - Fair Labor Standards Act, 2 folders (Box 7)
          - New York State Disability Benefits #1 (Box 7)
          - Workmen's Compensation Act (Box 7)
        - Pure Food
          - Black Jack (Box 7)
          - Brands and Packings-Monthly Samples, 1944-1956 (Box 7)
          - Fieldmint Oil, Canada and U.S. (Box 7)
          - Florida State Board of Health, Registration of Products (Box 7)
          - Great Britain, Labels on Packages (Box 8)
          - Indiana (Box 8)
          - Labels on Packages (Box 8)
          - Medicated Brands Policy (Box 8)
          - National Association of Chewing Gum Manufacturers (Box 8)
          - Nebraska (Box 8)
          - Registration with Board of Pharmacy (Box 8)
          - Returns of Spoiled Goods (Box 8)
          - Roumania (Box 8)
          - Sanitary Code of City of New York (Box 8)
          - Sodium Silico Fluoride (Box 8)
          - South Dakota-Use of "Imitation" on Kiss Me Grape Gum (Box 8)
          - South Dakota vs. California Fruit (Box 8)
          - U.S.-Albert T. Calder Company, Inc. (Box 8)
          - U.S. vs. Beeman's Pepsin Adams Pepsin Tutti Frutti (Box 8)
          - U.S. vs. California Fruit and Tutti Frutti (Box 8)
          - U.S. vs. Crawford's Cough Gum (Box 8)
          - United States Shipping Act, Freight Rebates, etc. (Box 8)
          - Use of Talc in Confectionery (Box 8)
          - Use of Word "Antiseptic" (Box 8)
        - War Revenue Act (Box 8)
      - Lawsuit
        - American Chicle Company vs. Superior Manufacturing Company, 3 folders (Box 8)
        - Federal Trade Commission vs. Big Bear Stores (Box 8)
        - Legal and Monetary Affairs Sub-Committee vs. Dentine Advertising (Box 8)
        - Superior Plumbing and. Heating Service vs. American Chicle Company (Box 8)
      - Lawsuits
        - Adams vs. Somerville (Box 8)
        - Aetna Acceptance Company vs. R.A. Grubbs (Box 8)
        - Wm. Aikman et al vs. American Chicle Company (Box 8)
        - American Chewing Products Corp. vs. American Chicle Company (Box 8)
        - American Chicle Company vs
          - Amber Products (Box 8)
          - City of Rochester (Box 8)
          - Somerville Paper Box Company, Ltd. (Box 8)
          - Standard Bank of South Africa, Ltd. (Box 8)
          - British Honduras (Box 8)
          - Long Island Railroad (Box 8)
          - Mexico (Box 8)
          - L. Ordenez and Silva (Box 8)
          - Charles Wagenseil (Box 8)
        - Antonius vs. American Chicle Company (Box 8)
        - Atwood Arnold and Company vs. American Chicle Company (Box 9)
        - L.M. Carroll vs. Rahall (Box 9)
        - Chu Moar. Gum Company vs. Bubble Balloon (Box 9)
        - Consumers Supply Company vs. American Chicle Company (Box 9)
        - Simon Cooper vs. American Chicle Company (Box 9)
        - Corning Glass Company (Box 9)
        - Federal Trade Commission vs.
          - American Chicle Company
            - [General], 1941; 1948,; 1949-1950; 7 folders (Box 9)
            - Chicle Dainties (Box 9)
            - Vending Operation (Box 9)
          - Automatic Canteen Co. of America, 2 folders (Box 9)
          - Bunte Bros., Inc. (Box 9)
          - Clorets (Box 9)
          - Dentyne, 2 folders (Box 9)
          - Life Savers Corporation (Box 9)
          - Morton Salt Company (Box 9)
          - Peter Paul (Box 9)
          - Seagram and Schenley (Box 9)
          - Sunshine Biscuits, Inc. (Box 9)
          - Sure Laboratories (Box 9)
          - Topps (Box 9)
        - Graves Quinn Corporation vs. American Chicle Company (Box 9)
        - Groton Realty Company vs. American Chicle Company (Box 9)
        - Gum, Inc. vs. Sweets Laboratories (Box 9)
        - Health Products (Feenament) vs. Ex-Lax Manufacturing Company (Box 9)
        - Jupp Agency vs. Marion Legrand and American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Kellogg Company (Shredded Wheat) vs. National Biscuit Co. (Box 10)
        - La Plante and Dunklin vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Larson vs. Wrigley (Box 10)
        - E. Mc Kee and E. Higbee vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Mirson vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Mitchell vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - New York Fire Department vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Sim L. Nichols vs. National Tube Company (Box 10)
        - O.P.A. vs. Mars, Inc. (Box 10)
        - Ozog vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - A. Palmerini vs. Board of Transportation (Box 10)
        - William J. Paul vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Peguot Manufacturing Co. vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Perman Company vs. Paul Santangelo (Box 10)
        - Dorothy Poynton vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Mr. Pracanico vs. Compania (Box 10)
        - Manuel Serrano vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Shores-Mueller Co. vs. Palmer (Box 10)
        - State of New Jersey vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - State of Texas vs. Harper (Box 10)
        - Unknown Claimant vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - Sheridan P. Wait, Jr. vs. American Chicle Company (Box 10)
        - West Coast Manufacturers and Exporters, Inc. vs. American Chicle Co. (Box 10)
      - Lease
        - Canada
          - Chocolate Products, Ltd. (Box 10)
          - Colgate-Palmolive-Peet Co. (Box 10)
          - Coulter Mfg. Co., Ltd. (Box 10)
          - General (Box 10)
          - Harrolds Coal Co. (Box 10)
          - W.H. Iverson and Co. (Box 10)
          - Mantle Lamp Company (Box 10)
          - Phin Sales Company (Box 10)
          - Reliable Mfg. Co. (Box 10)
          - Standard Cycle Prod. (Box 10)
          - Standard Upholstering Co. (Box 10)
          - Vancouver Warehouse (Box 10)
          - Winnipeg Warehouse (Box 10)
        - Charge for Electrical Current (Box 10)
        - L.I.C. [Long Island City]
          - Columbia Metal Hose, 3 folders (Box 10)
          - Levien, Ross, Bickwitt and Tommarchi (Box 10)
          - National Carbon Co (Box 10)
          - Owens-Illinois Distributors, Inc. (Box 10)
          - Royal Mounters (Box 10)
          - Sackett and Wilhelms Corporation (Box 10)
          - Sackett and Wilhelms Corporation, 2 folders (Box 11)
          - Standard Lease Form (Box 11)
          - Wilbur-Suchard Chocolate Company (Box 11)
        - Mexico
          - Antonio Hissa Chahlin (Box 11)
          - I.L. Rebuelta de Manoy (Box 11)
          - Sanborn Brothers (Box 11)
        - New Jersey
          - Camden Warehouse (Box 11)
          - Lackawanna Term. Whse. (Box 11)
          - Lehigh Warehouse and Transportation Company (Box 11)
          - Newark Central Whse., 2 folders (Box 11)
        - New York Office
          - 405 Lexington Avenue (Box 11)
          - 420 Lexington Avenue (Box 11)
        - North Pier Terminal Warehouse (Box 11)
        - San Francisco Factory, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - License
        - Alabama (Box 11)
        - Delaware (Box 11)
        - Hawaii (Box 11)
      - License Agreement, Brazil (Box 11)
      - License Arrangements, Foreign Subsidiaries (Box 11)
      - License, Food Delivery, Illinois (Box 11)
      - License
        - Peddler's
          - Alabama, Bessemer, Birmingham, Greenville, State and Jefferson and Chambers Counties; 4 folders (Box 11)
          - Arizona (Box 11)
          - California, 6 folders (Box 11)
          - Georgia (Box 12)
          - New Jersey (Box 12)
        - Plates, L.I.C. (Box 12)
        - Plates, Michigan (Box 12)
        - Privilege license, Tennessee (Box 12)
        - State and County Occupational, Florida (Box 12)
        - Wholesale Distributors
          - California, 4 folders (Box 12)
          - Florida (Box 12)
          - Louisiana (Box 12)
          - Oregon (Box 12)
      - Manufacturing Plant, Synthetic Base (Box 12)
      - Mexico, Counterfeit Premiums (Box 12)
      - National Labor Relations Act (Box 12)
      - National Production Authority, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - E.V. Moore, Personal (Box 12)
      - Ownership (Box 12)
      - Passing of Title on Sale of Goods (Box 12)
      - Patent Infringement Guarantee Clause (Box 12)
      - Pennsylvania Food Act (Box 12)
      - Pension Plan (Box 12)
      - Pensions, Canada, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Permit
        - Alcohol, Federal (Box 12)
        - Alcohol, Registration of Stills (Box 12)
        - Combustible (Box 12)
        - Fuel Oil Storage (Box 12)
        - Marquee on 47th Ave. Side of our Building (Box 12)
        - Place of Assembly (Box 12)
        - Refrigeration (Box 12)
        - Smoking and Tobacco (Box 12)
        - State of New Jersey (Box 12)
      - Permits, General (Box 12)
      - Personnel, Company Advances or Loans (Box 12)
      - Personnel, General (Box 12)
      - Powers of Attorney
        - Foreign Subsidiaries (Box 12)
        - U.S. Customs (Box 13)
      - Printing on Cellophane (Box 13)
      - Publications
        - "Getting Acquainted" Booklet (Box 13)
        - Journal of Commerce (Box 13)
        - Prentice-Hall, Inc. (Box 13)
        - "We Observe", "Current News" (Box 13)
        - "Your Job" Booklet (Box 13)
        - [General], 1948; 1950-1955 (Box 13)
      - Purchase and Sale of Company Stock (Box 13)
      - Purchase of Stock by Employees (Box 13)
      - Purchases, Chlorophyll (Box 13)
      - Qualifying [States and Countries], 3 folders (Box 14)
      - Ray Dent Company, Inc., 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Reduction of Good Will (Box 15)
      - Registration of Commercial Slogans (Box 15)
      - Reports
        - Fats and Oils, 1954-1962; 4 folders (Box 15)
        - GR-S Latex, 1954-1958; 1962; 3 folders (Box 15)
        - Sugar, 1955 (Box 15)
      - Reproduction of Letters for Advertising Purposes (Box 15)
      - Resignations (Box 15)
      - Sales Manual (Box 15)
      - Securities Exchange Act, 1934-1948; 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Sen Sen Confection, Suspension from Price Control (Box 16)
      - Sen Sen Confectionery Sign (Box 16)
      - Sen Sen Flavor, Musk Tincture Partial (Box 16)
      - Sen Sen Formula Custodian Agreement (Box 16)
      - Sen Sen Formula Registration in India (Box 16)
      - Sen Sen, Revised Formula (Box 16)
      - Services of Langer, Parry, Card, and Langer (Box 16)
      - Statutory Agents, various states (Box 16)
      - Stock Purchase Plan for Jobbers and Retailers (Box 16)
      - Stockholders' Rights (Box 16)
      - Storage of Chicle in New Jersey (Box 16)
      - Suggestions from Outsiders (Box 16)
      - Surplus Cash Investments (Box 16)
      - Tax
        - Commercial Vehicle, Colorado (Box 16)
        - Commercial Vehicle, Kansas (Box 16)
        - Imported Materials (Box 16)
        - Liens (Box 16)
        - Outdoor Advertising (Box 16)
        - Sen Sen, Brazil (Box 16)
        - Sen Sen, Argentina (Box 16)
        - Stock Transfer (Box 16)
        - Timbre Matter, Mexico (Box 16)
      - Taxes
        - Alcohol (Box 16)
        - General, 1948-1958; 3 folders (Box 16)
        - Increase in Capital Stock (Box 16)
        - Tax Calendar (Box 16)
      - Ultra Vires (Box 16)
      - Unclaimed Wages
        - John Sosnowski (Box 16)
        - L. Ungerhayer (Box 16)
      - Use of Artificial Colors (Box 16)
      - Use of "Cellulin Wrapped" (Box 16)
      - Use of our Trade Marks by Others (Box 16)
      - Use of "Squeeze Box" Container for Sen Sen (Box 16)
      - W.B. White (Box 16)
      - Wire Floor Display Racks (Box 16)
    - Notes, Releases (Box 16)
    - Patents
      - John C. Barker (Box 17)
      - Canada
        - Beatty Moisture Proof Package (Box 17)